Hello.
哈喽
Does this work?
能听见吗？
Can you guys hear me?
大家能听到我说话吗？
Will, can you hear me?
能听到吗？
Okay, sick.
OK 很好
All right, hey, everyone.
大家好
How's it going?
最近怎么样？
We are going to be doing software engineering 2.
今天我们要讲的是软件工程 2
The second installation of our software engineering series should be a lot of fun.
这是我们软件工程系列课程的第二部分 应该会很有趣
As you may notice, though, I am not Peyron, nor am I Justin.
大家可能已经注意到了 我不是 Peyron 也不是 Justin
We are completely different people.
我们是完全不同的人
So really quickly, who am I up here?
那简单介绍一下我自己吧
My name is Dominic.
我叫 Dominic
I'm one of the TAs for the course.
我是这门课的助教之一
I'm a senior in CS, and this is my fifth time teaching CS61B.
我是计算机科学专业的四年级学生 这是我第五次教授 CS61B 了
I've been around for a while, and I've seen a lot of good and a lot of bad software from a lot of students.
我已经在这待了挺久了 见过很多学生写的好软件 也见过很多写得很糟糕的软件
And what we're going to try to talk about today is how to get you on the upper end of that spectrum.
今天我们要讨论的是如何帮助大家写出更好的软件
In my experience, I've worked in the aerospace industry for a while.
我之前在航空航天业工作过一段时间
I'm Vanessa. I'm a junior majoring in CS and environmental econ and policy.
我是 Vanessa  我是一名大三学生 主修 CS 和环境经济与政策
This is my fourth semester on staff.
这是我在助教团队的第四个学期
I have two cats.
我养了两只猫
Their names are Fish and Chips.
它们分别叫“小鱼”和“薯条”
I also have done a lot of work with machine learning and infrastructure.
我还做过很多机器学习和基础架构方面的工作
So yeah, that's kind of my background.
这就是我的背景
All right, cool.
So the idea for today's lecture is going to be how to build a project from the ground up.
那么 今天这节课的主题将是如何从头开始构建一个项目
And we're going to walk through each part
我们将逐步讲解
of the design stage, the implementation stage, where we go from there.
设计阶段的每个部分、实施阶段 以及后续步骤
And especially, we're going to talk about how this is relevant to Project 3, because you're going to be given a blank file, blank slate, and you're going to try to build up from scratch.
我们会特别讨论这与 Project 3 的相关性 因为你们将获得一个空白文件 一块空白画布 需要从头开始构建
So we're doing general Q&A at the end if you have any questions.
如果你们有任何问题 我们将在最后进行问答环节
So let's jump into it.
让我们开始吧
OK.
好的
First stage is design.
第一个阶段是设计
All right, so raise of hands, how many of you have procrastinated on an assignment and started too late and had to cram?
举手示意一下 你们中有多少人曾经拖延作业 开始得太晚 不得不临时抱佛脚？
OK, for those of you who don't have your hand up, your eyes are incredibly cracked, or I don't believe you.
对于那些没有举手的人 要么是你们的眼睛睁不开了 要么是我不相信你们
Because I know everyone has done this, including myself.
因为我知道每个人都这样做过 包括我自己
The issue with this is you end up piling on a lot of technical debt, something we talked about in the previous software engineering lecture.
这样做的问题是 你最终会积累大量的技术债务 我们在之前的软件工程课上讨论过这个问题
And here's a quote that I hear from students far, far too often.
以下是我经常从学生那里听到的一句话
Instead of wasting time designing my program, I can save time by starting to code now, said by a person who will regret their decision very, very, very soon.
与其浪费时间设计程序 不如直接开搞 这是那些很快就会后悔自己决定的家伙说的话
And I tell this to you because I don't want you starting Project 3 five days before the deadline, four days before the deadline, and saying, I actually don't have time to write a design doc.
我这么说是因为不想看到你们在 Project 3 截止日期前五天、四天才说：“我真没时间写设计文档了”
I'm just going to start coding right away.
我还是直接开写吧
I'm here to tell you that design is an important first stage of development for the following reasons.
我来告诉你 设计是开发中重要的第一步 原因如下：
First of all, spending time to design your code before you actually start writing anything ensures consideration of all requirements and constraints.
首先 在真正开始写代码之前花时间设计可以确保考虑所有需求和限制
In the context of this class, this means that you actually think about the spec, how you're going to meet every part of the spec, and how you're going to pass all those tests.
就这门课而言 这意味着你得仔细考虑规范 如何满足规范的每一部分 以及如何通过所有测试
I've seen so many times students code out their entire project and then realize at the end, oh, I missed part of the spec.
我见过太多学生把整个项目代码写完后才意识到：“哦 我漏掉了规范的一部分”
And this requires going back, changing their code, rewriting a lot.
这就需要回头修改代码 重写很多东西
I do not want to see this.
我不想看到这种情况
This also happens in industry.
这种情况在业界也时有发生
When people forget, for example, to integrate security into their program, then all of a sudden they have to go back,
例如 当人们忘记将安全性集成到程序中时 他们就不得不回头
try to work security into a program which is already fully fleshed out, which just results in a poor, bad implementation on every side.
试图将安全性融入到已经完全成型的程序中 这只会导致各个方面的糟糕实现
It considers multiple alternatives and their relative advantages and disadvantages.
它考虑了多种方案及其相对优缺点
Something I see a lot is people pick the first thing that comes to mind, the easiest thing that comes to mind,
我经常看到人们选择第一个想到的东西 也就是最简单的东西
But oftentimes, your first thought is not your best thought.
但通常 你的第一个想法并不是你最好的想法
And if you start going down one way, you may realize that you failed to consider that this program actually has some constraints, which this way may not actually be able to achieve.
如果你开始朝一个方向走 你可能会意识到你没有考虑到这个程序实际上有一些限制 而这种方法实际上可能无法实现
It identifies potential costs or pitfalls while change is cheap.
它可以识别潜在的成本或陷阱 而改变的成本很低
Another thing I see a lot is when students start coding, they will run into a bug.
我经常看到的另一件事是 当学生开始编码时 他们会遇到 bug
And then they'll say, oh, actually, I can fix this really quick with a couple of Band-Aid lines.
然后他们会说：“哦 实际上 我可以用几行补丁代码快速解决这个问题”
It works. They move on.
它可以工作  他们继续前进
Another bug pops up.
又出现一个 bug 了
Oh, I can throw on a couple more patches.
哦 我可以再打几个补丁
This happens enough times, suddenly you have 20, 30 patches.
这种情况发生多了 突然间你就有了 20、30 个补丁
Your entire code base is patches, not actually something that's meant to work.
你的整个代码库都是补丁 而不是真正能用的东西
And then eventually, one way or another, it just all goes kabloom.
然后最终 总有一天 它会全部崩溃
Everything goes bad, and you have no idea how anything works because your code is just patches on top of patches.
一切都会变糟 你完全不知道任何东西是怎么工作的 因为你的代码只是补丁叠补丁
This isn't very fun. But something that I see a lot from students is they'll say, well, it would be so much effort to restart that I don't even want to start from scratch again.
这不好玩  但我经常看到学生们说 重新开始需要付出太多努力 我甚至不想从头再来
I would rather just keep pushing forward with this buggy implementation.
我宁愿继续推进这个有 bug 的实现
You're falling victim to the sunk cost fallacy.
你陷入了沉没成本谬误
In reality, we can avoid this by spending time to think about what a good design would be up front so we don't have to take the time to start from scratch over again.
实际上 我们可以通过花时间思考好的设计是什么来避免这种情况 这样我们就不必花时间从头再来
And lastly, it allows multiple minds to weigh in and leverages diverse perspectives.
最后 它允许多种思想参与进来 并利用不同的观点
By actually taking the time to write down what you want your program to do on a design document, this becomes something you can easily disseminate within your team.
通过花时间在设计文档中写下你希望你的程序做什么 这将成为你可以在团队中轻松传播的东西
For example, if you're at a company, you can give it to a manager or a more experienced dev, and then you can have them take a look at it.
例如 如果你在一家公司 你可以把它交给经理或更有经验的开发人员 然后让他们看看
It's a lot easier than you trying to think off the top of your head, what do I actually want this program to do while talking to someone?
这比你试图在脑子里想 我到底想让这个程序做什么 同时和别人说话要容易得多
And it may change person to person.
而且它可能因人而异
So now that we're on the same page about why design is important, how do we think about design in a formal way?
所以现在我们对为什么设计很重要有了共识 我们如何以正式的方式思考设计呢？
And we're going to do that through design documents.
我们将通过设计文档来做到这一点
So a design document is a form that doesn't necessarily have a specific format, but should give the reader easily accessible information about your project.
所以设计文档是一种形式 它不一定有特定的格式 但应该向读者提供关于你的项目的易于访问的信息
And in particular, a good design document should quickly bring the reader up to speed with what the intent of your program is and how it's going to work.
特别是 一份好的设计文档应该让读者快速了解你的程序的意图以及它将如何工作
include alternatives that were considered and why the trade-offs were made.
包括考虑过的替代方案以及做出权衡的原因
An important part of a design document is not just to say, here's how we did it, but actually to explain, here's what I thought about, and here's why I didn't go with it.
设计文档的一个重要部分不仅仅是说明“我们是怎么做的” 而是解释“我的想法是什么”以及“为什么我没有采用它”
Because at the end of the day, you want to explain and justify why your direction is the best direction.
因为最终 你需要解释并证明为什么你的方向是最佳方向
Years later, if someone is coming back to your project, maybe achieving yourself,
几年后 如果有人回到你的项目 也许是你自己
And you think, actually, why don't I do this a different way?
你会想 实际上 为什么我不换个方式做呢？
If your design doc explicitly states, oh, I thought about doing that,
如果你的设计文档明确指出 “哦 我考虑过这样做
but I didn't do it because perhaps it is too much of a memory issue, or it takes too long, don't do this.
但没有这样做 可能是因为内存问题太大 或者耗时太长 所以不要这样做 ”
It serves as a sign for future readers who will be using your code.
这可以作为未来使用你代码的读者的一個警示
should be just as much about the why as the how.
应该既要说明“怎么做” 也要说明“为什么”
People can read your code, and if it's written OK, they can figure out how it's working.
人们可以阅读你的代码 如果写得还行 他们就能明白它是如何工作的
But that doesn't really tell anyone why it is the way that it is.
但这并不能真正告诉任何人为什么它是这样的
And that's really what's most important in a design doc.
而这才是设计文档中最重要的一点
And lastly, it should update as a project progresses and be a living document.
最后 它应该随着项目的进展而更新 并成为一个活文档
So it's probably the fact that as you progress in your project, you will not 100% adhere to your design doc.
随着项目的进展 你可能不会100%地遵守你的设计文档
You will probably realize things which could have been different, and that's completely OK.
你可能会意识到有些事情可以做得不同 这完全没有问题
You don't need to stick by it in a hard and fast way.
你不需要一成不变地坚持它
In fact, oftentimes the best justification in a design doc is, I tried it and it did work, or I tried it and it didn't work.
事实上 设计文档中最好的理由通常是 “我试过了 它确实有效” 或者“我试过了 它没有效”
So it's OK to not adhere strictly to the design doc.
不严格遵守设计文档是可以的
And I hope that when you go on and you make big software projects in the future, and you create nice design docs for them,
我希望当你继续前进 在未来做大型软件项目 并为它们创建漂亮的设计文档时
when you revisit them in a year or two, maybe when you're onboarding the new intern to your project, or you're teaching the new employee,
当你在一两年后重新审视它们时 也许当你为你的项目加入新的实习生
how do you use my piece of software, you get a chance to reflect on, when I made this design doc, did I make the right decisions?
或者教新的员工如何使用你的软件时 你能有机会反思 当我做这个设计文档时 我做出了正确的决定吗？
Or should I have done something else?
或者我应该做些别的吗？
So in industry, how are design docs actually used?
那么在行业中 设计文档实际上是如何使用的呢？
Oftentimes, design docs get reviewed before work on the project even begins.
通常在项目开始前 设计文档会先经过评审
That's often the first task that you'll get.
这通常是你接到的第一个任务
They'll say, OK, we want to make this change, or we want to implement this feature.
他们会说 好 我们想要做这个修改 或者我们想要实现这个功能
Come up with a design doc.
写个设计文档吧
Show me how it's going to work.
告诉我它会如何运作
And when onboarding to an existing project, the first question that you or someone will ask is, where's the design doc?
当你加入一个现有项目时 你或其他人会问的第一个问题是 设计文档在哪儿？
So I want to give us a little bit of a glimpse into what that looks like in the real world.
所以我想让大家了解一下它在现实世界中的样子
Chromium is a free, open-source web browser developed and maintained primarily by Google,
Chromium 是一个免费的开源网页浏览器 主要由 Google 开发和维护
but it's the basis for a lot of web browsers like Google Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Opera Browser,
但它是许多网页浏览器的基础 比如 Google Chrome、Microsoft Edge、Opera 浏览器
And it's a pretty big project, but they've done a really good job of keeping documentation for everything.
它是一个相当大的项目 但他们做了很好的工作 为所有内容都保留了文档
So I want to show us what this looks like.
所以我想展示一下它是什么样子
So they have this big page with design docs for each aspect of this Chromium browser.
他们有一个很大的页面 包含了 Chromium 浏览器各个方面的设计文档
And say that I want to build my own browser on top of Chromium.
假设我想在 Chromium 的基础上构建自己的浏览器
And say something that I care about a lot, that I want to work on, or I want to change, is one of my favorite features, the Find Bar.
假设我非常关心 想做或想改变的事情 是我最喜欢的功能之一 查找栏
So that Control-F, and I can search up whatever I want on the page.
就是那个 Control-F 我可以在页面上搜索任何我想找的东西
So I can go ahead, and I can actually use this to look for the Find Bar.
所以我可以继续 我实际上可以用它来查找查找栏
And I'll see, oh, they have a design doc for the Find Bar.
然后我会看到 哦 他们有一个查找栏的设计文档
And let's see what I can determine based on this documentation.
让我们看看我根据这份文档能确定些什么
OK.
好的
So right away, I guess I can zoom in a little bit.
马上 我想我可以放大一点
What do I know about the Find Bar for this big project?
对于这个大项目 我对查找栏了解多少呢？
Right away, I'm told what it is.
马上就有人告诉我这是什么
And I see that this is a proposal for an upgrade to the find bar.
我看到这是一个关于改进查找栏的提议
I'm told at present how it works.
他们告诉我目前它是如何工作的
I see what part of the code I need to look at.
我了解到我需要查看代码的哪一部分
OK, it's owned by this web content view win thing.
它属于这个 WebContentViewWin 的东西
And I see how it's implemented.
我明白了它是如何实现的
OK, there's something called a widget win that I have to go look for in the code if I want to find it.
有一个叫做 WidgetWin 的东西 如果我想找到它 我得在代码里找找
OK, so what about the justification for this change that we're going to make, or that this design doc is proposing?
那么我们为什么要做这个改变 或者说这个设计文档提议的改变 有什么理由呢？
So here it explicitly states to increase the flexibility of this API that exists, and to enhance the consistency of bits in Chrome something something.
所以这里明确指出 要增加现有 API 的灵活性 并增强 Chrome 中某些部分的一致性
So this design doc outlines, OK, what is this design trying to improve upon?
所以这份设计文档概述了 这个设计试图改进什么？
And let's see what their intent behind this is.
让我们看看他们背后的意图是什么
And we can see down here the next sentence, the general intent of this design is that, and then blah, blah, blah, maybe some stuff I need to read up upon.
我们可以看到下一句话 这个设计的总体意图是 然后是一些我可能需要阅读的东西
OK, so right off the bat, within the first three paragraphs, I understand the context of the system I'm working on, the intent behind the design, and the justification for why we're doing it.
所以一开始 在前三段中 我就了解了我要处理的系统的上下文、设计背后的意图以及我们这样做的理由
If I scroll down a little bit, what do I see?
如果我往下滚动一点 我看到了什么？
I see, OK, there's this cool diagram.
我看到了 这里有一个很酷的图表
I see there's some class called the BrowserView, and it implements some interface.
我看到有一个叫做 BrowserView 的类 它实现了一些接口
We've seen diagrams like this.
我们见过这样的图表
We have some interface.
我们有一些接口
We have an arrow pointing to the class that implements that interface.
有一个箭头指向实现该接口的类
Then I even see we have some inheritance going on here, perhaps.
然后我甚至看到这里可能还有一些继承关系
If I scroll down, I get some more information.
往下滚动就能看到更多信息
I see that, oh, the way that these classes communicate is there's this thing called a notify-find-result-available.
我发现这些类之间是通过一个叫做 Notify Find Result Available 的东西来通信的
So immediately, I know if I want to change things, I can look for these parts of the code, and I know how they interact with one another.
所以我立刻就知道 如果我想修改代码 我可以找到这些部分 并且知道它们是如何相互作用的
Now, of course, this is one piece of a very large project.
当然 这只是这个大型项目中的一部分
What you're building in Build Your Own World, Project 3, is probably just going to be one part of that.
你在“构建你自己的世界 项目 3”中构建的东西可能也只是一部分
All right.
好的
So let's put this into context with what we're trying to build.
让我们把它放到我们想要构建的东西的上下文中
So in project three, we want to think about each class as we create them and how they all fit together.
所以在项目 3 中 我们希望在创建每个类时考虑它们是如何组合在一起的
Putting everything into one file will probably make you very sad.
把所有东西都放在一个文件里可能会让你很头疼
Ideally, each class should have a single role.
理想情况下 每个类都应该只有一个角色
And it's up to you to determine what a role is.
而这个角色是什么由你决定
But ideally, if you have a class that is both generating rooms and hallways, moving your avatar, keeping track of the score,
但理想情况下 如果你的类既要生成房间和走廊 又要移动你的角色 还要记录分数
Saving and loading files.
保存和加载文件
You might want to ask yourself, what is the role of this file?
你可能要问问自己 这个文件的角色是什么？
And if it's taking on too many roles, am I adding too much complexity to my project?
如果它承担了太多角色 是不是给我的项目增加了太多的复杂性？
Consider in each of your classes what message it should have to complete that functionality.
考虑每个类应该具有哪些消息来完成该功能
And a good benchmark is each message should ideally have one purpose.
一个好的基准是每个消息最好只有一个目的
We have a couple major algorithms that I want to just jog your mind about.
我想提醒你们几个主要的算法
You want to create rooms and generate hallways.
你们要创建房间并生成走廊
And I'll emphasize that you are making something new, even though you're all working on the same assignment.
我要强调的是 你们正在创造新的东西 即使你们都在做同样的作业
You're starting from a blank slate.
你将从头开始
And I hope that you tackle this problem with the approach that what I'm making is something completely brand new that no student has ever made before.
我希望你解决这个问题的方法是 你要做的是全新的东西 是以前任何学生都没有做过的
And therefore, I need to actually care about the design and the documentation that I'm putting into it.
因此 我需要真正关心我投入其中的设计和文档
All right, so with that, we'll go a little bit into managing complexity.
有了这些 我们再来谈谈管理复杂性
So does this game look familiar to anyone?
那么 这个游戏对大家来说熟悉吗？
Yeah?
是吗？
OK, kind of interesting.
有点意思
Well, for those who don't know, it used to come with a default version of Windows.
好吧 对于那些不知道的人来说 它曾经是Windows的默认版本
So you'd have a Windows computer or whatever, and you'd have access to this game.
所以你有一台Windows电脑什么的 你就可以玩这个游戏
You could just play it for fun, whatever.
你可以随便玩玩 随便玩玩
It's pinball.
这是弹球游戏
This game doesn't exist anymore on the newer versions of Windows.
这个游戏在新版本的Windows上已经不存在了
And so this game was originally made by a third party.
所以这个游戏最初是由第三方制作的
It wasn't made by Microsoft.
它不是微软做的
In the 2000s, many computers, they were getting upgraded from 32-bit systems to 64-bit systems.
在2000年代 许多计算机从32位系统升级到64位系统
Well, issues arose when we were porting from 32-bit to 64-bit systems.
好吧 当我们从32位系统移植到64位系统时 出现了一些问题
So in the end, this game doesn't exist anymore because
所以最后 这个游戏不存在了 因为
And this is because their code was so poorly written that no one could figure out how to possibly debug a small collision bug.
这是因为他们的代码写得太糟糕了 以至于没有人能弄清楚如何调试一个小的碰撞bug
In the end, Windows and Microsoft decided to just throw this game in the dumpster so it doesn't exist anymore.
最后 Windows和微软决定把这个游戏扔进垃圾箱 所以它不存在了
If you're like me, you probably don't want your work to end up like Space Cadet Pinball.
如果你像我一样 你可能不希望你的作品像Space Cadet Pinball一样
Like, you want to see your work last.
你肯定希望自己的作品能长久保存下来
I don't want to see, like, my two years of hard work just go, oh, like, bye, like, here's some, like, dumb collision error, and then now we can't no longer have our game anymore.
我不希望自己两年的辛苦工作付诸东流 比如 突然出现一个愚蠢的碰撞错误 然后我们的游戏就玩不成了
So this leads us to the idea of technical debt.
这就引出了技术债的概念
Dan mentioned it a little bit earlier.
Dan 之前稍微提到过一点
But so far in your classes, you've been coding for yourself, or you've been coding for an autograder.
但到目前为止 在你们的课程中 你们一直在为自己编写代码 或者为自动评分系统编写代码
So you're just working on an assignment, and you're just rushing through just to finish it, submit to the autograder, receive full credit, close your computer, and call it a day.
所以你只是在赶作业 匆忙完成它 提交给自动评分系统 拿到满分 然后关上电脑 结束一天的工作
But unfortunately, that's not how coding usually works.
但不幸的是 编码通常不是这样工作的
So in general, your code will be available to other people.
一般来说 你的代码会提供给其他人使用
So when we're coding for ourselves, we don't really care about the quality of our code.
所以当我们为自己编码时 我们并不真正关心代码的质量
But rather, we don't really care that others can understand it.
或者更确切地说 我们并不真正关心其他人是否能理解它
We just want to get it done.
我们只想把它完成
But there's a lot to consider when we're working with others.
但是当我们与他人合作时 有很多事情需要考虑
So someone's going to see your work, and people are going to build off of it.
别人会看到你的作品 并在此基础上进行开发
And they should be able to comprehend and understand whatever you've created.
他们应该能够理解你所创造的一切
You want to be proud of whatever you're putting out there.
你希望为自己发布的作品感到自豪
You want to know that you might have to build off your code three years later.
你希望知道自己可能在三年后需要重新使用你的代码
Transition your code off to someone else after your internship or whatever.
在实习结束后或其他情况下 将你的代码移交给其他人
But you want to create something that you're really proud of.
但你想要创造出一些你真正引以为豪的东西
Ideally, your code should be flawless and well-documented.
理想情况下 你的代码应该是完美无缺且文档齐全的
But deadlines exist.
但截止日期是存在的
So we don't have infinite time to be working on making our code elegant, perfect, gorgeous to the eye, or whatever.
我们没有无限的时间来让代码变得优雅、完美、赏心悦目等等
This is the idea of technical debt.
这就是技术债务的概念
As you continue to build, you'll get cluttered by your hastily written codes.
随着你不断构建 你会被匆忙写成的代码弄得一团糟
This is because you'll have school deadlines.
这是因为你有学校的截止日期
You'll have grants, conferences.
你会有补助金、会议
Maybe you procrastinate a little too hard on a project.
也许你在一个项目上拖延了太久
But you'll have prototypical, hastily written code, which is obviously inevitable.
但你会有原型化的、匆忙写成的代码 这显然是不可避免的
So this pressure is common in both industry and academia.
所以这种压力在工业界和学术界都很常见
The pressure to achieve both quality and quantity.
在质量和数量上都要取得成功的压力
And so this is inarguably a trade-off.
所以这无疑是一个权衡
Prioritizing one will negatively affect the other.
优先考虑其中一个会对另一个产生负面影响
And this doesn't just apply to code.
这不仅仅适用于代码
It applies to life.
它适用于生活
And to deal with this, you can see a strategic versus tactical programming from Software Engineering 1, which was, I think, a week and a half ago.
为了解决这个问题 你可以看看《软件工程 1》中的战略编程与战术编程 我想那是一周半以前的事了
So the importance of this is that you want to think about what is good code?
所以重要的是 你要思考什么是好的代码？
Well, we'll have three main goals.
嗯 我们有三个主要目标
Good code is typically easy to read, understand, and change by someone else that's other than the original author.
好的代码通常很容易被除了原作者之外的其他人阅读、理解和修改
And so the three main goals are readability.
所以三个主要目标是可读性
The code should be easy to read and understand.
代码应该易于阅读和理解
It should be simple.
它应该简单
The code solutions should be straightforward without unnecessary complexity.
代码方案应该简洁明了 不要过度复杂
It should be testable.
代码应该是可测试的
The code should be easy to test and debug.
代码应该易于测试和调试
So why is this important?
为什么这很重要？
Well, it facilitates easier understanding, maintenance, and debugging of our code.
因为它能让我们更容易理解、维护和调试代码
You want to be able to spot the bugs easily.
你希望能够轻松发现bug
And it's difficult to do that when you have a 500-line method, right?
而如果你的方法有500行代码 那就很难做到 对吧？
Let's say that you're placing the debugger, you're placing a breakpoint.
假设你在设置调试器 放置断点
And if you're going through 500 lines in just one method to spot a bug, it's going to be a lot more difficult than if your code was just 20 lines long.
如果你要在同一个方法中检查500行代码才能发现bug 那肯定比你的代码只有20行时困难得多
It enhances collaboration and code readability, so you want your partner or your boss or whoever to be able to understand the flow of your code easily so they can add on to it or they can improve your code.
它能增强协作和代码可读性 这样你的伙伴、老板或任何人都能轻松理解代码的流程 从而能够添加或改进你的代码
It also directly impacts the success and scalability of your project.
它还会直接影响项目的成功和可扩展性
As mentioned before, you don't want your code to end up like Space Cadet Pinball when inevitably our systems are going to get upgraded
正如之前提到的 你不希望你的代码最终像Space Cadet Pinball那样
and become a lot better, so you want your code to be able to transition easily.
因为我们的系统不可避免地会升级 变得更好 所以你希望你的代码能够轻松过渡
So with that, we'll go a little bit into bad style.
所以接下来 我们会稍微讲一下糟糕的代码风格
Well, what is bad style?
那么 什么是糟糕的代码风格？
We'll have poor and inconsistent formatting.
我们会看到糟糕且不一致的格式
You'll have multiple styles mixed into the same project.
同一个项目中混合了多种风格
Here, we have something called snake case, camel case, screaming snake case, flat case, and kebab case.
这里 我们有蛇形命名法、驼峰命名法、尖叫蛇形命名法、扁平命名法和烤肉串命名法
These are just some cases that you might use to determine your variable names, but there's definitely a lot more.
这些只是你可能用来确定变量名称的一些命名法 但肯定还有更多
Let's say for your project you're using Snake Case and you're using Screaming Snake Case.
假设你的项目使用了蛇形命名法和尖叫蛇形命名法
Well, I don't know what the difference might be.
好吧 我不知道它们之间有什么区别
You might not know what the difference is, so you just want to keep it the same format so that you might not get confused as to what different things may be.
你可能不知道不同格式之间的区别 所以你想保持一致的格式 以免搞混淆
If you look at your code two years later and you're seeing different kinds of cases, you might think that they represent something else, but you're just not really sure.
两年后当你看到代码中各种各样的格式 你可能会认为它们代表着不同的含义 但又不确定
Also, it's really often to not overcomplicate your code.
还有 不要把代码搞得太复杂
So oftentimes, simple tasks are overcomplicated by unnecessary steps or convoluted logic.
很多时候 简单的任务会被不必要的步骤或复杂的逻辑弄得过于复杂
You could have a method that has 12 if conditions, 6 for loops, and it's just doing something that you could have done in four lines instead.
你可能有一个方法 里面有 12 个 if 条件 6 个 for 循环 但它做的事情其实用四行代码就可以完成
So you don't want to overcomplicate your code, and you don't want to have repetitive code that re-implements the same logic.
不要把代码搞得太复杂 也不要重复实现相同逻辑的代码
We've taught a lot about the idea of abstraction.
我们已经讲了很多关于抽象的概念
You want to write a method, and you want to keep using it over and over again so that you don't have to copy and paste the same thing every single time.
你应该编写一个方法 并反复使用它 这样就不必每次都复制粘贴相同的代码
An important note, we'll use the word refactoring a lot.
一个重要的注意事项 我们会经常用到“重构”这个词
It's the idea of changing your code to make things more organized without affecting the functionality.
它指的是在不影响功能的情况下 修改代码使其更有条理
Let's say that you finished a project, then you want to start refactoring your code to make it more legible and just have cleaner code.
假设你完成了一个项目 然后你想开始重构你的代码 让它更易读 更简洁
Before refactoring, you always want to add and commit your code.
在重构之前 你应该始终添加并提交你的代码
This way, you can restore your old work if necessary.
这样 如果需要 你可以恢复旧的工作
What this means is that, let's say that you just spent two days refactoring your code, right?
这意味着 假设你刚花了兩天时间重构你的代码 对吧？
Originally, your code worked perfect.
最初 你的代码工作得很好
You were just like, oh, well, this is a pain to look at.
你只是觉得 哦 这看起来太痛苦了
It's really ugly, so I'm going to make it look better.
它太丑了 所以我要让它看起来更好
And you spend two days refactoring, and then all of a sudden, something broke.
你花了兩天时间重构 然后突然 出现了问题
Like, you broke your code.
比如 你弄坏了你的代码
Oh, no, like, there goes my work.
哦 不 我的工作完了
At least you can restore to your original work, and you'll have your functioning code.
至少你可以恢复到原来的工作 并且你的代码还能运行
So let's take a look at this example.
我们来看一下这个例子
Does anyone know what's wrong with this?
有人知道这里有什么问题吗？
Any ideas?
有什么想法吗？
Anyone?
有人吗？
Yes.
有
You're way ahead of the game right here.
你已经领先一步了
What I was going to say is, I have no idea what's going on.
我本来想说的是 我不知道发生了什么
Looking at this code, the indentations are all messed up.
看看这段代码 缩进全乱了
I don't even know what it's going to do.
我甚至不知道它要做什么
But my best guess is that it probably prints 3D arrays.
但我最好的猜测是它可能会打印 3D 数组
You brought up a great point.
你提出了一个很好的观点
Maybe we'll use the toString.
也许我们会用到 toString
We'll see that in a little bit.
我们稍后会看到
So this is what we're trying to do.
这就是我们要做的
All I know is that we're trying to print a 3D array.
我只知道我们想要打印一个 3D 数组
I'm looking at this code.
我正在看这段代码
I can't tell what the hell it's doing.
我看不出它到底在做什么
We'll kind of look here.
我们来看看这里
The first thing I'll do is that I'll create a test in order to verify the correctness as I refactor.
我要做的第一件事是创建一个测试 以便在重构时验证正确性
I just want to write a little test, test my code, and confirm that it works.
我只是想写个小测试 测试一下我的代码 确认它能运行
So I run my small test here.
所以我在这个地方运行我的小测试
Hey, it works.
嘿 它可以运行
Why do we want to change it?
为什么要修改它呢?
You might think, if it ain't broke, why fix it?
你可能会想 如果它没有坏 为什么要修?
Well, here.
好吧 这里
You want to fix it, because what if you want to print 4D arrays, 5D arrays, 2D arrays?
你想修复它 因为如果你想打印 4D 数组、5D 数组、2D 数组怎么办?
What about an n-dimensional array, right?
n 维数组怎么办 对吧?
So it's not very easy to generalize, and so we want to refactor it.
所以它不是很容易泛化 所以我们想重构它
The first thing we'll do is that we'll use the tools of the language.
我们要做的第一件事是使用语言的工具
Here, this looks a little bit better than what we saw previously.
这里 这看起来比我们之前看到的要好一些
I'm using a for each loop here, and I'm iterating through my arrays.
我在这里使用 for each 循环 并且我正在遍历我的数组
And then my variable names are still a little jank, but I'm using what I've been given, right?
然后我的变量名仍然有点乱 但我正在使用我所得到的东西 对吧?
Still that bad, but much better, even with the terrible names.
仍然很糟糕 但好多了 即使名字很糟糕
I'll run my small test.
我运行我的小测试
Oh no, it doesn't work.
哦不 它不能工作
You might think, OK, I'm just going to give up.
你可能会想 好吧 我要放弃了
Whatever worked previously is fine.
以前任何有效的方法都可以
But that's not the mentality that we have.
但这不是我们的心态
So next, we want to separate our logic into simple methods.
接下来 我们想把我们的逻辑分成简单的方法
So notice that previously we used continue statements.
注意之前我们用了 continue 语句
Instead, now I'm just going to break this into print 3D array, print 2D array, and print 1D array.
现在我把它拆成 print3Darray、prin2Darray 和 print1Darray 三个函数
This way, if I see that I have a little bug, I can be able to fix it a lot easier.
这样如果发现小 bug 我就能更容易地修复它
I can step through each method and see what's happening as I'm going through it with a shorter method as opposed to a 30-line long method.
我可以单步执行每个方法 看看运行过程中发生了什么 短方法比 30 行的长方法更容易理解
So I'm looking here.
我看一下
It looks much better now.
现在看起来好多了
Our test still doesn't work.
测试还是没通过
This is what we're seeing here.
我们看到的是这个
We're seeing that everything is ending with a comma.
所有内容都以逗号结尾
It's looking kind of weird.
看起来有点奇怪
And the comma error is occurring in three different places, in the 1D array, in the 2D array, and the 3D array.
这个逗号错误出现在三个不同的地方 1D 数组、2D 数组和 3D 数组中
This probably means that there's some error in all of these methods, right?
这可能意味着所有这些方法中都存在一些错误 对吧？
It's not just in one central location.
它不只是在一个中心位置
So if I were to just put everything into one central location and change from there, I might be able to fix that comma bug.
所以如果我把所有内容都放在一个中心位置并从那里进行更改 我或许可以修复那个逗号错误
So maybe you want to consider using a generic type.
所以你可能要考虑使用泛型
You might notice that if we were doing this in an IDE, you'd actually have some sort of compiler error.
你可能已经注意到 如果我们在 IDE 中这样做 实际上会出现某种编译器错误
So what I'll do instead is that I'm just going to search up how to have static generic types in Java.
所以我接下来要做的就是搜索如何在 Java 中使用静态泛型
And I'm going to use Stack Overflow because We like Stack Overflow.
我要用 Stack Overflow 因为 我们喜欢 Stack Overflow
It's a very reliable source most of the time.
它在大多数情况下都是一个非常可靠的来源
And we'll see here, I have static, some sort of object, void, do it to this object.
这里我定义了一个静态方法 参数类型是泛型 返回值为空 作用于某个对象
Is it the first one or the second?
是第一个对象还是第二个？
First one.
第一个
Cool.
好的
So we'll kind of try out something that we searched on the internet.
我们来试试在网上搜到的方法
And so now we have this, static T, void, print, comma, separated.
现在我们定义了这个方法 静态的 泛型T 返回值为空 方法名是print 参数是用逗号分隔的
And I'm going to have all my code in this method so that I'm just calling the same method in print 2D array, print 3D array, and print 1D array.
我把所有代码都放在这个方法里 这样我就可以在打印二维数组、三维数组和一维数组时调用同一个方法
And so I'm just going to run my test.
我先运行测试
You can actually have generic static methods that we searched up earlier.
实际上 我们可以使用之前搜索到的泛型静态方法
And this is our output.
这是我们的输出结果
What the hell does any of this mean?
这都是些什么鬼？
Well, what's basically happening here is that we're just trying to, as you'll debug, you'll kind of notice that you're trying to print a nested array.
基本上 我们只是想... 当你调试的时候 你会发现你在尝试打印一个嵌套数组
So this means that I'm calling system.out.print on the array itself, not just the item.
这意味着我是在对整个数组调用 system.out.print 而不仅仅是数组中的元素
And so what I'll do here is that I am going to search up how to print arrays in Java.
所以我接下来要搜索如何在 Java 中打印数组
So the first thing we'll do, we'll take a look at, you know,
首先 我们来看看...
Our friends Stack Overflow.
我们的老朋友 Stack Overflow
And the first thing we'll see here is, oh, for a simple array, let's just call arrays.toString.
首先我们看到的是 哦 对于一个简单的数组 我们只需要调用 arrays.toString
So I am not going to try to code anything out.
所以我不想自己写代码
I'm just going to use whatever I saw on the internet.
我只想用我在网上看到的方法
And here, we're going to use system.out.print arrays.toString.
在这里 我们要使用 system.out.print 和 arrays.toString
And let's hope that this works.
希望这次能成功
And I get the same output.
然后得到相同的输出
Once again, this is because our program is nested.
再说一次 这是因为我们的程序是嵌套的
We have nested arrays inside of arrays.
我们有嵌套在数组内部的数组
And so once again, we're trying to print out another array, which just points to the pointer.
再一次 我们试图打印另一个数组 它只是指向指针
This is actually pretty annoying to resolve.
解决这个问题其实挺烦人的
You can try to do this in yourself without using the library solution.
你可以尝试自己做这件事 不用库的解决方案
But I'm lazy, so I'm going to go look a little harder.
但我懒 所以我要去更深入地研究一下
And I'm going to scroll a little down on Stack Overflow.
我要在 Stack Overflow 上往下滚动一点
And we're going to see here that they give us arrays.deepToString deepArray.
我们将在这里看到他们给了我们 arrays.deepToString deepArray
So we'll try that this time around and hope that it fixes everything.
所以这次我们将尝试一下 希望它能解决所有问题
And yeah, this works as desired.
是的 这按预期工作
We have that null in there, but this is our code in the end.
我们那里有 null 但这就是我们最终的代码
We have a null array here, but we want to have that.
这里有一个 null 数组 但我们希望有它
We want to know that we are passing in a null array.
我们想知道我们正在传递一个 null 数组
So that's what we want to have.
所以这就是我们想要的
And this now works for any amount of nested arrays and any non-primitive array type.
现在 这适用于任何数量的嵌套数组和任何非原始数组类型
This is our ending code.
这是我们的最终代码
This will help us print 5D arrays, 6D arrays, whatever we want.
这将帮助我们打印 5D 数组、6D 数组 任何我们想要的
And so this is our original code compared to our refactored code.
所以这就是我们原来的代码与重构后的代码的对比
This mess, horrific mess, compared to our one-liner.
跟我们简洁的代码比起来 这段代码简直一团糟
So you can see how some refactoring of our code has allowed us to come to this very easy, simple arrays.toString method.
通过代码重构 我们得到了一个简单易懂的 arrays.toString 方法
And that just saved us a lot of our time.
这节省了我们很多时间
Cool.
不错
With that, here's a quick bonus.
这里有个小彩蛋
So this is a game called Quake 3.
这是一个叫 Quake 3 的游戏
This is their fast inverse square root method.
这是他们使用的快速平方根倒数方法
This is actually in their source code.
这实际上是他们的源代码
So in 1999, people were making this game.
在 1999 年 人们制作了这款游戏
It's called Quake 3.
它叫 Quake 3
It's some 3D arena game.
这是一款 3D 竞技场游戏
So you can see how this guy is looking at this mirror.
可以看到这个人正在照镜子
It's pretty cool, pretty well-developed for its time.
它很酷 在当时来说开发得相当不错
There were a lot of lighting calculations.
有很多光照计算
And this required a lot of vector normalizations, just calculations.
这需要大量的向量归一化计算
I'm not going to go into the nitty-gritties here.
我就不细说了
This is coded in C. But let's take a look at this code.
这是用 C 语言编写的 我们来看看这段代码
All I can tell from looking at this is that 3 halves is 1.5.
我能看出来的是 3 的一半是 1.5
I got that.
我知道
But if you see here, this code is actually really, really fast.
但是你可以看到 这段代码实际上非常快
I'm not exactly sure how it works.
我不太清楚它是怎么运作的
Justin could probably explain it.
Justin 可能能解释一下
But it's super fast and efficient, and it was used in production of this game.
但它超级快 效率很高 而且这款游戏就是用它制作的
When they released their source code, everyone was like, oh my god, this is so fast and amazing.
当他们发布源代码的时候 每个人都惊呆了 这代码太快太牛了
How does it even work?
它到底是怎么工作的？
They look at this code, and they're like, damn, I don't think the developers knew what was going on either.
他们看着这段代码 心想：我靠 我觉得开发者自己都不知道怎么回事吧
But they plugged in this number, this long number, and it just kind of worked for them.
但他们填了一个数字 一个很长的数字 然后它就莫名其妙地能用了
You know, like these are the original comments posted in their source code.
你知道 这些是他们源代码里最初的注释
So hopefully your comments look better than this and magic numbers are pretty bad.
所以希望你的代码注释能比这好点 而且魔法数字真的很糟糕
But only in 2018, I think like 20 years later, was some mathematical analysis found for how any of this code works.
直到 2018 年 我觉得是 20 年后 才有人对这段代码的工作原理进行了一些数学分析
But yeah, this is just some sort of example.
但这只是一个例子
You don't want your code looking like this.
你不希望你的代码看起来像这样
So with all of this, you want to follow good style conventions.
你需要遵循良好的代码风格规范
So if you want to have good styles, you can follow these kind of guidelines.
如果你想拥有良好的代码风格 可以参考这些指南
We'll have the Google Style Guide.
我们有 Google 代码风格指南
This gives you a general convention guide on every single language.
它为每种语言提供了一般性的规范指南
We also have our 61B Style Guide.
我们还有 61B 代码风格指南
And so you might be wondering, why are we so anal about our style guide?
你可能会想 为什么我们对代码风格指南这么严格？
You submit a project, you're like, yay, I finished.
你提交了一个项目 心想：耶 我完成了
And then you get a zero because you didn't have another space.
结果因为你少敲了一个空格 就得了零分
In your if statement, well, we really do emphasize the importance of style because every company has its preferences.
在 `if` 语句中 我们真的很强调风格的重要性 因为每家公司都有自己的偏好
You want to follow their conventions, right?
你想遵循他们的规范 对吧？
No matter how good of a programmer you are, you're not going to be a good addition to a company or whatever, like, if you cannot follow their conventions.
无论你编程技术有多好 如果你不能遵守他们的规范 你就无法成为公司或其他任何地方的优秀员工
This could maybe lead to, like, I don't know, like, not getting a return offer, maybe, like, even termination.
这可能会导致 比如 拿不到 return offer 甚至可能被解雇
Those might be some extreme cases.
这些可能是一些极端情况
But we just want to emphasize that it's important to follow conventions that you're given.
但我们只是想强调 遵循给定的规范很重要
This is not a complete list of guidelines.
这不是一个完整的指南清单
Here's just some interesting ways that you can follow clean code.
以下是一些编写简洁代码的有趣方法
And so to summarize, writing clean code is really difficult.
总而言之 编写简洁的代码真的很难
It's really hard.
真的很困难
Refactoring is difficult.
重构很难
You're not changing the functionality of any of your code.
你没有改变任何代码的功能
You're just making it cleaner.
你只是让它更简洁
So you didn't necessarily do anything to our code.
所以你并没有对我们的代码做任何事情
We didn't add any features.
我们没有添加任何功能
We didn't add anything else.
我们没有添加任何其他东西
But rather, we just made it more legible so that it's all an investment in the future.
而是让它更易读 所以这一切都是对未来的投资
There's no immediate clear gains.
没有立竿见影的收益
Right now, maybe I just want to print out 3D arrays.
现在 也许我只想打印 3D 数组
The original code worked, but what if in the future I want to print out a 4D array?
原来的代码可以工作 但如果将来我想打印 4D 数组呢？
I'm working with some hyperspaces or whatever.
我正在处理一些超空间之类的玩意儿
You're going to want to have more dimensions or more features.
你肯定希望有更多的维度或特征
So the more that's built on top of your bad code, the worse your problem gets.
在糟糕的代码上构建得越多 问题就越严重
It's really hard to tell what will break.
真的很难说哪些地方会出问题
And so the more that you work, the more will break the longer you wait.
所以你工作得越多 等待的时间越长 出问题的可能性就越大
So the idea here is that you don't want your code to end up like Space Cadet Pinball.
所以这里的想法是 你不想让你的代码最终变成像 Space Cadet Pinball 一样
You want your work to be sustainable.
你希望你的工作是可持续的
And so you want to code cleanly from the beginning.
所以你想要从一开始就干净地编写代码
With that, we'll dive a little bit into documentation and how to document your code.
有了这些 我们将深入探讨文档以及如何记录你的代码
So documentation is a technology that, in technology, it refers to various written materials that accompany software or systems.
所以在技术领域 文档是指伴随软件或系统的各种书面材料
So it can cover a broad spectrum, including code comments, API documentation, user manuals, design specifications, test documents.
所以它可以涵盖很广的范围 包括代码注释、API 文档、用户手册、设计规范、测试文档等等
etc.
等等
So what this means is that you might have little comments, a part of your code, you might have a readme, you might have a design doc
所以这意味着你可能有一些小的注释 作为你代码的一部分 你可能有一个 readme(自述) 文件
that we mentioned earlier, you might have little blurbs explaining what every single test does.
你可能有一个我们之前提到的设计文档 你可能有一些小片段解释每个测试的作用
This is all considered documentation.
这些都被认为是文档
So for now, we'll just concentrate on practical documentation strategies that you can use for your projects, your assignments, whatever, especially Project 3 today.
所以现在 我们将只关注一些实用的文档策略 你可以将它们用于你的项目、作业 等等 尤其是今天的 Project 3
So why do we need it?
那为什么我们需要它呢？
Well, I've heard this phrase a lot, like, oh, we don't have enough time.
嗯 我经常听到这句话 比如 哦 我们没有足够的时间
Well, quick documentation now avoids longer explanations later.
嗯 现在快速记录文档可以避免以后更长的解释
Let's say that you're in office hours, you're explaining your code, or you're just trying to remember what's going on.
假设你在办公时间 你在解释你的代码 或者你只是想回忆发生了什么
You're sifting through 300 lines of code, and you're like, well, I don't remember what anything is.
你正在翻阅 300 行代码 然后你就会想 嗯 我不记得任何东西是什么了
I think this is supposed to do that, but I'm not 100% sure.
我觉得它应该能实现这个功能 但我不完全确定
So just having a quick comment on the side saying what you're doing, how it works, whatever, would help you explain, avoid longer explanations.
所以在旁边写个简短的注释说明你在做什么 它是如何工作的 等等 可以帮助你解释 避免冗长的解释
I've also heard, like, no one's going to read it.
我还听说过 好像没人会读它
I highly doubt it.
我非常怀疑
Well, it serves a guide for future developers and the users of your code.
嗯 它可以作为未来开发者和你代码用户的指南
As I mentioned earlier, let's say that you've completed your internship, you're transitioning to another intern.
就像我之前提到的 假设你已经完成了实习 你要交接给另一个实习生
Well, they're going to have to look at your documentation to see what anything is.
嗯 他们将不得不查看你的文档才能了解任何东西
It's essential for maintaining and scaling projects.
这对于维护和扩展项目至关重要
As mentioned earlier with Space Cadet Pinball, if you want to continue to scale your project for the future, having some documentation is going to be very necessary for understanding what anything really does.
就像之前提到的 Space Cadet Pinball 如果你想在未来继续扩展你的项目 有一些文档将是理解任何东西真正功能的必要条件
And in Project 3, your partner is really going to benefit from reading it.
在项目 3 中 你的合作伙伴将真正受益于阅读它
You're going to be working with a project partner, maybe not always consistently in sync, but your project partner has to be able to understand what any of your code does.
你将与一个项目合作伙伴一起工作 可能不会总是保持同步 但你的项目合作伙伴必须能够理解你的任何代码的作用
Also, it's kind of a funny comment, but I've heard the code should be self-documenting.
还有一个有点好笑的评论 我听说代码应该自文档化
Someone might say, oh, my code's pretty self-explanatory.
有人可能会说 哦 我的代码很容易理解
It should document itself.
它应该自己文档化
Well, would you rather read 100 lines of someone else's code, or would you rather just read a one-sentence summary?
嗯 你是愿意阅读别人 100 行代码 还是只阅读一句总结？
I don't want to spend another hour looking at your 20 lines of code, trying to be like, oh, OK, now I understand what you're doing, and then I'm going to continue.
我不想再花一个小时看你的 20 行代码 试图弄明白 哦 好吧 现在我理解你在做什么了 然后我将继续
So just having a little bit of documentation is really important.
有一点文档真的很重要
And so you want your documentation to explain why, in the context of what your code is, not just how your code works.
所以你希望你的文档解释为什么 在你的代码的上下文中 而不仅仅是如何工作的
And so here's a little example.
这里有一个小例子
What can we improve about this documentation?
我们可以如何改进这个文档？
Anyone?
有人吗？
What do we think?
大家觉得怎么样？
So I see here we have public Boolean movePlayer int x int y. I'm told that it changes the locations of the trees in the world, and we use java.util.random.
我看到这里有个公共布尔函数 movePlayer 参数是 int x 和 int y 据说它会改变世界中树的位置 并且使用了 java.util.random
What do we think we can improve here?
大家觉得这里可以改进什么？
Yes?
有人吗？
Exactly, yeah.
没错
We're told that it returns a Boolean, but we're not really sure, like, we're moving a player.
它说返回一个布尔值 但我们不太确定 比如 我们是在移动玩家
Like, what?
这啥意思？
And so also, like, are we moving trees?
还有 我们是在移动树吗？
Are we moving the players?
我们是在移动玩家吗？
Like, I'm told that we're changing the location of the trees, but I'm moving a player.
我听说是在改变树的位置 但我是在移动玩家
And why are we even using Java.util.random?
还有 为什么要用 java.util.random？
Like, am I moving the tree or the player, like, randomly from this current location?
我是随机移动树还是玩家 从当前位置随机移动？
Like, I have no clue, right?
我完全不知道 对吧？
And what are x and y?
x 和 y 是什么？
And so here's a better example of how you can document this.
这是一个更好的文档示例
It might be a little bit excessive, but you're told that you move the player to a specified location within the game world.
可能有点啰嗦 但它告诉你 将玩家移动到游戏世界中的指定位置
It validates the destination, and it checks for bounds.
它会验证目的地 并检查边界
You're told that your x and y-coordinates are the location of the destination, the horizontal and vertical positions.
它告诉你 x 和 y 坐标是目的地的位置 水平和垂直位置
You return true if the move is successful, and false otherwise.
如果移动成功则返回 true 否则返回 false
That explains our Boolean return type.
这就是我们返回类型为布尔值的原因
We throw an out-of-bounds exception, and then we're told that to move the player to
我们抛出一个越界异常 然后被告知将玩家移动到
This will save a lot of back and forth between you and your project partner.
这将节省你和你的项目伙伴之间来回沟通的时间
And so with good documentation of your code, you also want to have good documentation of your history.
代码要有良好的文档记录 历史记录也要有
And so you want to write good git commits when you finish your code and you're pushing it or you're just committing your code as a whole.
所以在完成代码并推送或提交整个代码时 要写好 git 提交信息
There are some well-established conventions, like capitalizing the subject line, using imperative mood.
有一些约定俗成的规范 比如主题行首字母大写 使用祈使语气
I'm going to show you how to do that in a minute.
我待会儿会告诉你具体怎么做
You're probably committing too many changes at once.
你可能一次提交了太多更改
Let's say that I finished my room generation, my hallway generation, my walls, my avatar, my background, everything, right?
假设我已经完成了房间生成、走廊生成、墙壁、角色、背景等等所有内容 对吧？
You're trying to commit six different things at once.
你试图一次提交六个不同的内容
That means that you've probably written like 500 lines of code, and then you're committing it at once, maybe more than 500.
这意味着你可能写了500行代码 然后一次性提交 甚至可能超过500行
So we want to kind of condense that and commit more often.
所以我们要尽量压缩一下 更频繁地提交
It's a good habit for us to have.
这是一个好习惯
Let's try adding the room generation logic and committing that once.
我们尝试添加房间生成逻辑并将其提交一次
And then fixing your overlapping rooms, committing that once.
然后修复房间重叠问题 再提交一次
This is in pretty chronological order.
这基本上是按照时间顺序进行的
I recommend starting your commit messages with a verb and then going on with whatever you've done.
我建议用动词开头写提交信息 然后写你做了什么
This will be good practice.
这会是一个好习惯
And so these are some good git commits that you might be able to see.
这些都是一些好的 git 提交信息示例
But here are some bad git commit messages.
但这里有一些不好的 git 提交信息示例
This is from when Justin and I were both students taking CS61B.
这是我和 Justin 还在上 CS61B 课程时留下的
This is from two years ago when my comment messages were just, yikes, like, please, like, please, please, please work, like, please.
这是两年前的 我当时的提交信息简直是... 呃 求求了 求求了 求求了 求你了 能运行吧 求你了
Or like, this one's not bad, like, fixed nulls.
或者像这个 这个还不错 修复了空值
And then Justin is just fixing bugs for decades.
然后 Justin 几十年来一直在修复 bug
And then he added some bugs.
然后他又增加了一些 bug
So this is actually both from when we were working on Build Your Own World, and this just shows that, like, we do it too.
所以这些实际上都是我们在开发 Build Your Own World 时留下的 这表明 我们也会犯这样的错误
Like, we've done it as students, but now we're working on writing, like, more comprehensive Git commit messages so that at least other people are, like, aware of what is going on.
就像 我们以前作为学生犯过这样的错误 但现在我们正在努力写更全面的 Git 提交信息 这样至少其他人能知道发生了什么
And so to summarize, basically, poor documentation can impact productivity in three main areas.
所以总结一下 基本上 糟糕的文档会在三个主要方面影响生产力
The first thing is searchability.
第一件事是可搜索性
Time lost is often lost a lot in deciphering and navigating code.
时间浪费往往发生在破译和浏览代码的过程中
If you have a lot, a lot of code in one file, well, you're going to have to sift forever to be looking for whatever you're trying to do and trying to explain what your code is doing.
如果你在一个文件中有很多很多代码 那么你将不得不花费大量时间来寻找你想要做的事情 并试图解释你的代码在做什么
And then you might end up rewriting the same code multiple times.
然后你可能会多次重写相同的代码
Let's say that you have some crucial method hidden in the middle of your 600,000 line of code, right?
假设你有一些关键方法隐藏在你 60 万行代码的中间 对吧？
Well, if you have a quick comment saying what it is and where it does, you'll be able to revisit it and abstract this idea multiple times.
好吧 如果你有一个简短的注释说明它是什么以及它做什么 你就可以多次重新访问它并抽象化这个想法
You don't want to just be rewriting the same wrapper method that just does the same thing in every single method instead of just calling a function.
你不想只是在每个方法中重写相同的包装方法 而只是调用一个函数
Then it'll be easier to onboard.
然后 onboard(加入) 会更容易
Everyone's implementations are different, right?
每个人的实现方式都不同 对吧？
Let's say that you're onboarding your project partner.
假设你正在加入你的项目合作伙伴
You've started working on your grids or your world generation or whatever, and you think that the origin 00, the coordinates, should be in your bottom left.
你已经开始着手你的网格或世界生成等等 你认为原点 00 坐标应该在你的左下角
What if your project partner just thinks that your coordinates are in the top left, right?
如果你的项目合作伙伴认为你的坐标在左上角怎么办 对吧？
They think 00 is in the top left.
他们以为 00 在左上角
I'm going to show you how to do that in a minute.
我待会儿会演示怎么做
And then in office hours, you'll be onboarding core staff onto your project.
然后在办公时间 你要让核心人员熟悉你的项目
So you might notice that we have around 10 minutes to help students in office hours.
你可能注意到了 我们在办公时间只有大约 10 分钟来帮助学生
Well, let's say that you're spending seven minutes explaining your code to your TA or tutor, AI, or whatever, right?
假设你花了 7 分钟给助教、AI 导师之类的解释你的代码 对吧？
That means that you'll have around three minutes to have actual debugging help in office hours.
那就意味着你在办公时间只有大约 3 分钟来获得真正的调试帮助
This is because you spent so long being like, oh, I have a method that is supposed to do this, but I'm not really sure.
这是因为你花了太多时间说 “哦 我有一个方法应该可以做到这个 但我不太确定”
And we're looking at your illegible, incomprehensive, and undocumented code.
然后我们看着你那难以辨认、无法理解、没有文档的代码
Well, I also have no clue what's going on.
我也不知道发生了什么
If you just spend time to, like, make your code legible and to document your code, you'll probably have three minutes of
如果你花点时间让你的代码易读并写好文档 你可能会有 3 分钟时间
onboarding the core staff onto your project and what you're doing, and then that gives us seven minutes to help you debug your code.
让核心人员熟悉你的项目和你正在做的事情 然后这给了我们 7 分钟来帮助你调试代码
And then we've seen some industry examples, what might happen with, like, an internship, a job, whatever, and with, like, our pinball game.
然后我们已经看过一些行业例子 比如实习、工作之类的 还有我们的弹球游戏
You'll see the importance of having well-written and well-documented code.
你会看到写好代码并写好文档的重要性
And then finally, you want to know that Project 3 is going to be a partner-based project.
最后 你要知道 Project 3 将是一个基于合作伙伴的项目
And so you and your partner will be working and writing code that both of you should understand.
你和你的伙伴将一起工作并编写你们俩都应该理解的代码
So you're working as a team.
所以你们是一个团队
If one partner can't understand any of the code that you wrote, let's say that you wrote an entire file of code,
如果一个伙伴无法理解你写的任何代码 比如你写了一个完整的文件的代码
and your partner can't understand any of it, well, you'll have to spend the time explaining it to them, or you're just setting yourself up to do all the work, too.
而你的伙伴却无法理解其中的任何内容 那么你就得花时间向他们解释 或者你只是让自己做所有的工作
If no one else can understand your code, how do you expect anyone to use it?
如果没人能理解你的代码 你如何期望别人使用它？
So we'll go a little bit into how to work in a team.
所以我们会稍微讲一下如何在团队中工作
All right, cool.
很好
So we're going to switch gears a little bit.
所以我们要稍微转换一下思路
We've been talking about industry applications of software.
我们一直在讨论软件的行业应用
And most of this course has been technical things, which you can memorize, perform on a test.
这门课主要讲授的是技术知识 需要记忆和考试
I'm going to talk a little bit about a soft skill.
接下来 我会讲一些软技能
But I hope you take it just as seriously, because it is indeed a skill that you can develop and one that will help you
希望大家重视它 因为这是一种可以培养的技能 它会帮助你在 Project 3 以及未来的职业生涯中受益
both in Project 3 and hopefully the rest of your career.
无论是 Project 3 还是未来的职业生涯
So some context.
先介绍一些背景
Project 3 is a partner project.
Project 3 是一个合作项目
We're doing teams of two, as has been done in most of the recent past.
我们采用两人一组的形式 和最近的大多数项目一样
Two main reasons.
主要有两个原因
One, we want you to get practice working on a team.
第一 我们希望大家练习团队合作
And two, it is a really open-ended project, so we want you to get some creativity flowing.
第二 这是一个非常开放的项目 我们希望激发大家的创造力
We think it should be a lot of fun.
相信大家会玩得很开心
And it also should reduce the programming workload a little bit.
同时 这也应该会减轻一些编程工作量
Although, the main point of this project is not the workload.
不过 这个项目的主要目的不在于工作量
The workload should be a little bit less than the previous projects.
工作量应该比之前的项目少一些
It's small enough that oftentimes a single person can handle it.
项目规模不大 一个人通常也能应付
The main goal is that partnership and creativity are what we're trying to emphasize.
我们的主要目标是强调合作和创造力
But teamwork is hard.
但团队合作很难
In the real world, a lot of projects and tasks are too difficult to be handled by a single person.
在现实世界中 许多项目和任务过于复杂 无法由一个人完成
That's why we have software companies and not everything is an indie development.
这就是为什么我们有软件公司 而不是所有项目都是独立开发的
But when faced with the same task, some teams succeed and other teams fail.
但面对同样的任务 有些团队成功了 有些团队失败了
Last semester, for Build Your Own World, around 9% of partnerships rated their experience a 2 out of 10 or 1 out of 10, sorry, 2 out of 5 or 1 out of 5.
上学期 在“构建你自己的世界”项目中 大约 9% 的合作伙伴给他们的合作体验打了 2 分或 1 分（满分 5 分）
indicating that they hated their partnership.
这表明他们讨厌他们的合作伙伴
Man, those are some brutal comments.
天呐 这些评论太残酷了
We asked people to describe the split of work between how much they did, how much their partner did.
我们让大家描述一下他们和合作伙伴之间工作量的分配情况
Some people were like, 95-5, I hated my partner.
有些人说 95% 对 5% 我讨厌我的搭档
So what can we do to be better partners and make this experience better?
那么 我们怎样才能成为更好的合作伙伴 让这种体验变得更好呢？
The idea behind partnership projects is it should be better for everyone.
合作项目的理念是 它应该让每个人都受益
So why is it the case that some people are having a worse time when we're giving you more people to work with?
那么 为什么当我们给你更多的人一起工作时 有些人反而会更糟呢？
I'm going to take a little bit of a detour, and then we're going to come full circle.
我要稍微绕个弯 然后再回到正题
So just to establish some context, I'm going to work on some of Spearman's work.
为了建立一些背景 我要研究一下斯皮尔曼的一些工作
He's an OG psychologist from the past century.
他是上个世纪的一位元老级心理学家
And here, this guy, Woolley, explains some of his work, which is quite foundational.
在这里 这位名叫伍利的家伙解释了斯皮尔曼的一些工作 这些工作相当基础
So here's a quote.
这是一段引言
People who do well on one mental task tend to do well on most others, despite large variations in the test's contents and message of administration.
在一项心理测试中表现出色的人 往往在大多数其他测试中也表现出色 尽管测试的内容和管理方式存在很大差异
So this mysterious factor that showed us that some people are just better at problem-solving around the board is called intelligence.
这个神秘的因素表明 有些人就是更擅长解决各种问题 这就是智力
And intelligence is easily measured.
智力很容易衡量
There are a couple tasks which you can give to someone.
你可以给某人布置一些任务
And within an hour, I can get a number that ranks someone's intelligence.
在一个小时内 我就能得到一个数字 来衡量某人的智力水平
And this isn't just, oh, how good are you at solving LeetCode hards?
这不仅仅是 哦 你解决 LeetCode 难题的能力有多强
Or can you integrate in your head?
或者你能心算吗？
Intelligence is actually correlated, and this has been replicated a bajillion times, with important long-term factors like grades in school, success in occupations, and even life expectancy.
智力实际上是相关的 这一点已经被无数次地证实 与重要的长期因素相关 例如学校里的成绩、职业上的成功 甚至预期寿命
And I'd like to note that there's nothing in Spearman's work that says that this factor is genetic.
我想指出的是 Spearman 的研究中没有任何内容表明这个因素是遗传的
So later on, this wooly guy in 2010 set about trying to figure out, well, can we apply intelligence to groups?
所以后来 这个满脸胡茬的家伙在 2010 年开始尝试弄清楚 嗯 我们能把智力应用到群体中吗？
Is there a reason why some groups are good and others are bad?
有些群体好而其他群体差 这是有原因的吗？
And he found that, indeed, we can see an analogy between individual intelligence and group intelligence.
他发现 我们可以看到个体智力和群体智力之间的类比
That is that some groups, which are better at solving a particular task, are better at solving any task.
也就是说 有些群体更擅长解决特定任务 也更擅长解决任何任务
And, of course, his goal was to figure out, why is this the case?
当然 他的目标是弄清楚 为什么会这样？
Why do some groups succeed and others fail?
为什么有些群体成功而其他群体失败？
You would probably assume that this has something to do with maybe average intelligence of the group, or the most intelligent person in the group,
你可能会假设这与群体成员的平均智力 或者群体中最聪明的人有关
But in fact, this was not the case.
但事实并非如此
And instead, there were three factors which Woolley found that were most highly correlated with group intelligence.
相反 研究者 Woolley 发现有三个因素与群体智力最为相关
Firstly, is the average social sensitivity of the group members.
首先 是群体成员的平均社会敏感度
And you would think this is kind of like an ephemeral conceptual idea.
你可能会认为这有点像一个短暂的概念性想法
But in fact, social sensitivity is the ability to perceive and understand the emotions of the people around you.
但实际上 社会敏感度是感知和理解周围人情绪的能力
And this can actually be measured through this reading the mind in the eye test.
这实际上可以通过“读懂眼睛里的想法”测试来衡量
It's where you look at a picture of just someone's eyes and you try to guess what emotion they're feeling.
就是你看一张只有某人眼睛的照片 然后试着猜测他们的感受
I think it's really cool.
我觉得这真的很酷
You should try taking the test.
你应该试试这个测试
It's actually not that easy.
其实并不容易
It's kind of difficult.
这有点难
Secondly, how equally distributed the group was in conversational turn-taking.
其次 小组成员在对话轮流方面是否平等分配
So in groups where one person dominates the entire conversation, group intelligence was low.
所以在一个由一个人主导整个对话的小组中 群体智力水平较低
And lastly, and probably most interestingly, the percentage of females in the group.
最后 可能也是最有趣的是 小组中女性的比例
This is not to suggest that we should just fire all men from your company.
这并不是说我们应该解雇公司里的所有男性
The paper explains that this is probably due to a correlation between gender and social sensitivity.
该论文解释说 这可能是由于性别与社会敏感性之间的关联
So why do I care about this for Project 3?
那么 为什么我要在 Project 3 中关心这个呢？
Well, because the point of Project 3 is to help you develop those skills of group intelligence.
嗯 因为 Project 3 的目的是帮助你培养群体智力的技能
And although that you'll be coding Project 3 in Java, in IntelliJ, you'll be committing to Git,
尽管你们将用 Java 在 IntelliJ 中编写 Project 3 的代码 提交到 Git
and then submitting to Gradescope, all technical skills, I hope you recognize that this project is about teamwork as well.
然后提交到 Gradescope 所有这些都是技术技能 但我希望你们认识到这个项目也与团队合作有关
And so I urge you to please treat each other with respect, be open and honest, and set clear expectations.
所以我恳请你们互相尊重 坦诚相待 并设定明确的期望
And if those expectations are not met, to confront this fact head on.
如果这些期望没有得到满足 要直面这一事实
So let's talk about how we can do this.
那么让我们来谈谈如何做到这一点
So reflexivity is a key word here.
所以反思是这里的关键词
And reflexivity is the group's ability to collectively reflect upon team objectives, strategies, and processes and adapt to them accordingly.
反思是指团队集体反思团队目标、策略和流程 并相应地进行调整的能力
And our recommendation is that you try to cultivate an environment where giving and receiving feedback happens on a consistent basis and is seen as a mechanism for reflection and learning.
我们的建议是 你们尝试培养一种环境 在这种环境中 给予和接受反馈是持续发生的 并被视为一种反思和学习的机制
And also, I'd like to note that it's OK for you and your project partner to be on different levels
另外 我想说的是 你和你的项目伙伴处于不同的水平是可以的
Everyone comes in at a different experience level.
每个人都来自不同的经验水平
Everyone progresses at a different rate.
每个人的进步速度都不同
So I would really like to emphasize understanding.
所以我真的想强调理解
It's OK if you feel like your project partner is moving really fast.
如果你的项目搭档进度很快 别担心
And try not to feel frustrated if you wish your project partner was doing more work.
如果你希望你的项目搭档多做点 也别沮丧
We're trying to develop those skills of empathy here.
我们正在努力培养同理心
I have this big document that I've grabbed from somewhere in Berkeley that explains best practices for teamwork.
我从伯克利某处找到了一份很大的文件 里面解释了团队合作的最佳实践
But I'm going to try to distill the most important parts of feedback that are going to help us with reflexivity.
但我打算提炼出关于反馈的最重要部分 来帮助我们进行反思
First off, giving feedback and receiving feedback is hard.
首先 给予和接受反馈都很难
It's important to acknowledge that, right?
承认这一点很重要 对吧？
I'm saying this, but can you imagine going up to your partner and saying, hey, I saw you at Kip's last Saturday.
这么说吧 你能想象走上前去对你的搭档说：“嘿 我上周六在 Kip's 看到你了 你知道我们项目进度落后了吧？”
You know we're behind on our deadlines, right?
你知道我们截止日期快到了 对吧？
I mean, that's uncomfortable for me to even say here.
我的意思是 即使在这里说出来 我也觉得很不舒服
It almost sounds like I'm accusing them I'm being mean.
这听起来像是我在指责他们 像是我在故意找茬
And that's normal, right?
这很正常 对吧？
Oftentimes, probably in your life, I know certainly in my life, I've received feedback that maybe the other person was trying to be constructive, but maybe I interpreted it as being rude.
通常情况下 可能在你的生活中 当然在我的生活中 我收到过一些反馈 也许对方是想表达善意 但我却认为他们很粗鲁
Maybe they were phrasing it in kind of a mean way.
也许他们的措辞有点刻薄
And because of this, I'm conditioned to maybe not be as receptive to feedback.
正因为如此 我可能已经习惯于不那么容易接受反馈
And I'm also scared to give people feedback, because what if they think it's me personally attacking them, right?
我也害怕给别人反馈 因为如果他们认为我是在针对他们怎么办 对吧？
But what I'll emphasize here is that, as we go into this project, try to assume best intentions from your teammates and try to believe that they believe in you as well.
但我要强调的是 在我们进行这个项目时 试着假设你的队友是出于好意 并相信他们也相信你
Feedback is also hard because, well, you're in the middle of a tough programming assignment.
反馈也很难 因为 你正在进行一项艰巨的编程任务
You're trying to finish the semester strong, right?
你想在学期结束时取得好成绩 对吧？
Why would I take the time to talk to my teammate about how our processes are, if we're getting along, when I really just care about getting the code done as soon as possible?
如果我们相处得很好 而我只关心尽快完成代码 那我为什么要花时间和我的队友讨论我们的流程呢？
In reality, I'll tell you that it's not a waste of time.
其实 花时间讨论一点也不亏
In fact, spending time in a system where neither you nor your partner feel like you're getting what you want to get out of the project is going to be a really, really bad experience.
你和你的伙伴如果都感觉没达到项目目标 那这种合作体验会非常糟糕
And you're much better off talking through the issues first before trying to go for the code.
最好先把问题说清楚 再开始写代码
And thirdly, feedback can simply be difficult to produce.
第三 反馈本身就很难
So you've probably had a lot of experience coming up with great algorithms, thinking about data structures.
你们可能都擅长设计算法 思考数据结构
This is not as easily attainable of a skill.
但给出有效反馈却不是那么容易
And if you don't have the confidence to give good feedback, then maybe you won't feel comfortable giving it until you're forced to give it.
如果没有信心 你可能就不太愿意主动反馈 除非是不得不说的情况
So what I want to push here is that we can try to be proactive with our feedback, try to learn how to give good feedback in advance, and this will set us up for success.
我们应该积极主动地去学习如何提供有效的反馈 这将帮助我们成功
OK, so we've talked about why feedback is important.
好 我们已经讨论了为什么反馈很重要
And I'm going to give us a strategy for maintaining consistent feedback as we work on Project 3.
我会分享一个策略 帮助大家在 Project 3 中保持持续的反馈
And what better way to do that than actually work with your partner in person?
有什么能比和你的伙伴面对面合作更好的方式呢？
So how many of you have tried pair programming before?
你们当中有多少人尝试过结对编程？
A couple of us.
我们中有几个人试过
OK, perfect.
太好了
So this will be a great opportunity to try it for a first time.
那么 这将是一个很好的机会来尝试一下
Pair programming is a technique where two people work together on a single station.
结对编程是一种两个人在一台电脑上一起工作的技术
And usually, there are two roles.
通常 有两种角色
This is the main way people do it.
这是人们常用的方式
There's a driver who's always focused on the design.
一个是驾驶员 专注于设计
Sorry, the driver is always focused on the implementation.
抱歉 驾驶员专注于实现
And the navigator is always focused on the design and the accuracy.
导航员始终关注设计和准确性
Earlier, we talked about how important it is to consider design.
之前我们讨论过考虑设计的重要性
Well, it doesn't matter if then you go coding and you completely ignore all of it.
如果之后开始编码并完全忽略设计 那就没意义了
So by having these two roles, you ensure that someone is always thinking about design.
因此 通过这两个角色 可以确保始终有人在考虑设计
Now, the typical rebuttal is, well, why can't we just work individually?
典型的反驳是 为什么我们不能单独工作？
Then we would have two times the productivity.
这样我们就会有两倍的生产力
But in reality, pair programming is very popular because it's often more productive than two people working individually
但实际上 结对编程非常受欢迎 因为它通常比两个人单独工作效率更高
because you reduce errors, reduce the time spent debugging, increase the code quality, and increase productivity.
因为它可以减少错误 减少调试时间 提高代码质量 并提高生产力
A couple of tips for this are to clearly define the roles, so make sure you know who's doing what.
一些建议是明确定义角色 确保每个人都知道自己在做什么
And people typically find every 15 to 30 minutes is a good interval to always keep yourself interested.
通常人们发现每 15 到 30 分钟是一个很好的间隔 可以保持兴趣
I'd highly recommend trying it out.
我强烈建议尝试一下
And even if you can't meet in person, there are online ways to do this with these extensions.
即使不能见面 也可以通过这些扩展程序在线进行
And lastly, even if you can't see each other face-to-face, you will want to keep each other up-to-date with what's going on.
最后 即使不能面对面 也要让彼此了解最新情况
In industry, you'll likely have stand-up, probably on a near daily basis.
在行业中 可能会有站立会议 可能几乎每天都有
And the important things to communicate when you're updating your progress are what you're working on, if anything is blocking your progress, and if you need feedback or advice from any other team member.
更新进度时需要沟通的重要事项包括：正在做什么 是否有任何阻碍进度的事情 以及是否需要其他团队成员的反馈或建议
And while you guys are all busy, you probably won't have the time to give daily 15-minute stand-ups every day.
虽然大家都很忙 但可能没有时间每天进行 15 分钟的站立会议
Keep each other up to date with progress.
让彼此了解最新的进展情况
I hope that our central theme throughout this lecture is communication is key.
我希望本次讲座的中心主题是沟通是关键
Communication through teamwork, communication through your design, communication through your documentation.
通过团队合作进行沟通 通过设计进行沟通 通过文档进行沟通
This is what we're really trying to emphasize.
这才是我们真正想要强调的
OK.
好的
I'll close with that, and we'll move into Q&A if anyone has any questions.
我就先讲到这里 如果大家有问题 我们可以进入问答环节
Yeah.
好
Oh, really good question.
哦 问得好
So the question is, if I'm not sure how to write a tile generation algorithm, where do I start?
问题是 如果我不知道如何编写地图生成算法 应该从哪里开始呢？
Something I did as a student was I would actually look at game blogs online.
我上学的时候会去看游戏博客
There are a lot of indie devs who completely open source everything they do.
很多独立开发者会开源他们的所有代码
There are so many interesting algorithms out there.
有很多有趣的算法
Feel free to read over them and draw inspiration or even try to implement the same thing that they're doing.
你可以阅读它们 从中获取灵感 甚至可以尝试实现它们的功能
Yeah, great question.
是的 好问题
Yeah.
嗯
I would say so.
我觉得是这样
I guess I'll say something and then Vanessa can speak.
我先说 然后 Vanessa 可以补充
My first internship, it was doing network routing stuff for satellites at NASA.
我的第一次实习是在 NASA 做卫星网络路由
And essentially, I just implemented Dijkstra's 2.0 for satellites.
基本上 我为卫星实现了 Dijkstra 2.0 算法
It was really cool.
真的很酷
Highly, highly recommend 61B.
强烈推荐 61B 课程
Yeah, I'd definitely say so.
是的 我绝对同意
It really helped with especially recruiting processes.
它对招聘过程很有帮助
A lot of recruiting focuses on data structures.
很多招聘都关注数据结构
That's the core of our entire course.
这是我们整个课程的核心
Yeah, like teaching 61B really helped me solidify all the material that I really needed to know for like an internship and everything that you needed to like get one and for industry.
教 61B 这门课真的帮我巩固了实习所需的所有知识 以及获得实习和进入业界所需的技能
All right, thanks everyone for coming.
谢谢大家今天过来
We'll stick around at the front if you have any questions.
如果你有任何问题 我们会在前面等你